Aparna Katiyar

Degree in Software Engineering with experience as a software developer, also served as business analyst for analyzing and optimizing CAD workflows and processes. Gathering business requirements, documenting and creating flowcharts for better understanding. Creative in finding solutions to problems, energetic presenter and a confident communicator.

🔀 aparnakatiyar2000@gmail.com

8076607650



in linkedin.com/in/aparna-katiyar-890543154/

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills
- Ability to translate business requirements into technical solutions through UML Diagram, flowcharts(BRD)
- SQL
- Excellent communication and collaboration abilities
- Visualization tools MS Excel, Power BI(Beginner), PowerPoint Presentation
- Understanding of agile methodologies and software development life cycle
- Scrum
- JIRA tool
- Google Analytics
- Product Management, Product requirements document(PRD)
- Product development life cycle
- Proficient in CAD software (e.g., AutoCAD, Inventor, Plant3D)
- C / C++, C#, .net, windows forms app, console app, LINQ
- Solidity Language(Basics) which is used for Smart Contracts in Blockchain
- Git

EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer

Haldor Topsoe Jun 2022 - Jul 2023

CAD Software:

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams (design, engineering) to identify process improvement opportunities and optimize CAD workflows.
- Brainstormed with product manager and business remotely to understand, refine the requirements, process and deliver the features.
- Created requirements specifications, UML diagrams that decreased requirement gathering and analysis time by 50%.
- Facilitate design sessions across design and business to identify the acceptable solution and created user stories accordingly.
- Helped maintain user satisfaction.
- Prepared and participated in project design reviews and gave demonstrations of new features.
- Reduce the work life cycle and enhance the quality of output for Autocad designers.
- Assisted in the testing and validation of CAD software updates and enhancements.
- Recommended design modifications to eliminate component system malfunctions.

AutoCad

- Created addin for autocad for automating the manual process of creating ECO in vault after the drawing is checked into vault from autocad and sent to share along with the pdf.
- Developed UI within the process for choosing ECO or creating new ECO and adding roles accordingly.
- Updated existing addin of a diagram created using VB.Net according to the requirements of mechanical users.
- Created addin which works on new template specifically and captures values of all the attributes of drawing.
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.

• Debugging application to ensure low latency and high availablity, fixing bugs, maintenance taks, etc.

Vault

Updated code in C# for updating the roles of ECO from activity history of vault and send it to share after getting
picked by job processor.

Plant3D

Bug fixes for terminating the cad support forum to pop up after changing the workspace.

CPQ Application:

- Created and maintained business requirement and project related documents.
- Worked on trampoline code which is used for integration of Salesforces and CPQ platform, mapping attributes.

Software Engineer

Virtual Engineering Services Pvt. Ltd Aug 2023 - Present Inventor:

- Created addin for inventor in C# using inventor api for automatically modelling a manifold block with specified dimensions and for modifying the block size.
- Created inventor addin for relocating the manifold block to a new location by specifying the X and Y values from the origin.
- Addin for rotating a 2D sketch in inventor by specifying the point of rotation and angle.
- Created extrude and revolve feature using inventor api.

POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY

Param Society - Technical Society of College

MGM College 2021-07-29

Deputy Head - Recruited students for the scoiety, organised technical workshops.

Param Society - Technical Society of College

MGM College 2020-02-29

Technical Team Member - Organised tachnical workshops, bootcamps, etc for college students.

EDUCATION

B.TECH

MGM College Of Engineering and Technology, Noida Jun 2018 - Jun 2022

Percentage - 70.4%

Higher Secondary

Assisi Convent School, Noida 2018

PCM

Percentage - 67.50%

10th Standard

Assisi Convent School, Noida 2016

CGPA - 9.2

CERTIFICATION

Introduction to Analytics

Great Learning

Blockchain Basics

Coursera

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

SCIENCE UTSAV

Science Promoter – Organised workshops for children to promote science

Upay NGO

Music

Worked as a volunteer to teach underprivileged children

LANGUAGES		
English	Hindi	
HOBBIES		
Sketching	Cycling	Reading books

Volunteer work